Manish Patil

JAVA | NODE JS | REST API | Micro Services | AWS | DevOps | Mentorship | Troubleshooting

Phone: +1 562 270 7500

Email: manish0890@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/manish-patil-167162108

Github: https://github.com/manish0890

PROFESSIONAL SUMMERY

I have over 7 years of work experience as a Software Engineer, and I am passionate about learning new technologies and skill sets so I can utilize that knowledge along with my leadership skills to solve the problems and improve business solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, C#.NET, Shell Scripting, JSON, YAML, HTML and CSS
- Databases: Elasticsearch, MongoDB, MySQL, MS SQL
- AWS stack: EC2, S3, SQS, SNS, Lambda functions, Elasticsearch, RDS
- DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Gitlab CI, Jenkins, Netlify, Azure cloud, Kibana, Grafana
- Project Management Tools: JIRA, Microsoft TFS
- Tools: Swagger, Postman, Dynatrace, Twistlock, SonarQube

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

■ Northwestern Mutual, Manhattan, NY | 03/26/2018 - Present

Title: Technical Lead

Java Spring boot, Spring Web-flux, NodeJS micro services, ExpressJS, ReactJS, Elasticsearch, REST APIs, Swagger docs, AWS Lambda functions, SQS, SNS, S3, EC2, Kibana, Dynatrace, SonaQube, JUnit5, Maven Responsibilities:

- Develop highly scalable micro services in Java Spring boot, Spring Web flux and NodeJS
- Containerize services and deploy them on AWS cloud using modern CI pipelines like GitlabCI
- Use AWS SQS, SNS for better resource management and availability, Develop Lambda functions to maximize app scalability
- Design Systems from scratch, Improvise Designs and Architectures according to the new functional / performance requirements
- Mentor and train junior developers for optimized programming, debugging and software troubleshooting
- Arrange team building and career building exercises like innovation sprints, hackathon
- Axway Inc., Phoenix, AZ | 11/16/2015 03/15/2018

Title: Automation Engineer

Docker, Docker Swarm, Chef, Shell Scripting, Azure Cloud deployments, Gitlab, CICD, Deployments, On Prem to Cloud migrations, Test Automation, Postman

Responsibilities:

- Develop Node.js and Java services with container technology including Kubernetes, Docker, and AWS ECS
- Cloud platform including AWS and Microsoft Azure
- Migrate application from on premise setup to cloud technology and write deployment scripts in Shell and Chef
- Used Jenkins and Gitlab-CI for Continuous Integration and Deployment
- Aetna Healthcare, Phoenix, AZ | 03/30/2015 11/11/2015

Title: Application Developer

ASP.NET, C#, SSIS BI tool, SSRS reporting, MS SQL, Stored Procedures, TFS, ClearCase,

Responsibilities: Develop Web Applications in ASP.NET for frontend designing. Design and debug T-SQL Queries and Complex Stored procedures. Develop SSIS packages with inline SQL queries and SQL server Stored Procedures. Generate standalone reports and database dependent dynamic reports using SSRS reporting tool

■ eGumball Inc., Irvine, CA | 12/29/2014 – 03/17/2015

Title: Junior Developer

C# MVC5, Razor View Engine, Classic ASP, PHP, E2E Testing, MySQL

Responsibilities: Migrate Classic ASP websites to ASP.NET MVC 5 Web apps, perform E2E testing and fix issues

EDUCATION

California State University, Long Beach | USA | August 2013 – May 2015 | GPA 3.5 Master of Science in Computer Science

AISSMS Institute Of Information Technology | India | August 2008 – November 2012 | 61%

Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Science